Let's build off the grid world example and investigate how we might
我们构建网格示例
determine the value function corresponding to a particular policy.
并研究如何确定对应特定策略的值函数
To begin, we'll enumerate the states.
首先 我们将枚举各个状态
So, state S1 is the state in the top left corner,
状态 S1 是左上角的状态
then S2, S3, and S4.
然后是 S2 S3 和 S4
Say, we're trying to evaluate the Stochastic Policy where
假设我们尝试评估随机性策略
the agent selects actions uniformly from the set of possible actions.
即智能体从一组可能的动作里平等地选择动作
For instance, in state S1,
例如 在状态 S1
the agent either moves right or down and it essentially decides by just flipping a coin.
智能体可能向右或向下移动 它只是通过抛掷硬币来决定
That is, it moves right with 50 percent probability and otherwise, moves down.
也就是说向右移动的概率是 50% 向下移动的概率也是 50%
In state S2, it moves left half of the time and moves down the other half of the time.
在状态 S2 它向左移动的概率是 50% 向下移动的概率是 50%
The same goes for state S3,
状态 S3 也一样
where the agent moves up with 50 percent probability and otherwise moves right.
智能体向上移动的概率是 50% 向右移动的概率是 50%
So, how about we determine the state value function corresponding to this policy?
我们推理下该策略对应的状态值函数
Let's begin with recording what we know about state S1.
我们先记录关于状态 S1 的信息
So, half the time, the agent moves right.
智能体向右移动的概率是 50%
In the event that the agent does move right,
当智能体的确向右移动时
the expected return it collects can be calculated as negative
它收集的预期回报可以计算为
one plus the value of the state S2 that it lands on.
-1 加上下个状态 S2 的值
And the other half of the time,
在剩下的 50% 概率下
the agent moves down and the resultant expected return is
智能体向下移动 得出的预期回报为
just negative three plus the value of the next state S3.
-3 加上下个状态 S3 的值
So then, the value of state S1 can be calculated as the average of these two values.
状态 S1 的值可以计算为这两个值的平均值
Since the agent chooses each of the potential actions with equal probability,
因为智能体选择这两个潜在动作的概率一样
you might recognize this equation as just the Bellman equation evaluated at the state S1.
你可能发现该方程式就是在状态 S1 时评估的贝尔曼方程
Here we see that it let's us express the value of
我们看到该方程式使我们能够
state S1 and the context of the values of all of its possible successor states.
根据所有可能的后续状态的值表示状态 S1 的值
Continuing with state S2,
继续看看状态 S2
if the agent moves left,
如果智能体向左移动
the expected return is negative one plus the value
预期回报是 -1 加上状态 S1 的值
of the state S1 and if the agent moves down,
如果智能体向下移动
the expected return is five plus the value of the terminal state S4.
预期回报是 5 加上最终状态 S4 的值
And to get the value of state S2,
为了获得状态 S2 的值
we need to just take the average of these two values.
我们需要对这两个值取平均值
And here we've arrived at the Bellman equation again but now, for state S2.
我们再次得出了贝尔曼方程 不过这次针对的是状态 S2
We can continue the trend for state S3 when we take into account that
我们可以继续按照这种方法查看状态 S3
the agent can move up or right and we take the average of the two values.
智能体可以向上或向右移动 计算这两个值的平均值
Finally, the value of the state S4 will always be zero since it's a terminal state.
最后 状态 S4 的值将始终为 0 因为它是最终状态
After all, in the case that the agent starts at the state,
因为如果智能体从该状态开始
the episode ends immediately and no reward is received.
这一阶段将立即结束 没有任何奖励
In this way, we see that we have one equation for each state and we
这样 我们就得出了每个状态的方程式
can directly solve this system of equations to get the value of each state.
我们可以直接对该方程组求解 得出每个状态的值
And when you solve the system,
当你解该方程组时
you get these values where the values of state S1 and of
会得出这些值 其中状态 S1 和最终状态均为 0
the terminal state are both zero and each of the other two states has a value of two.
另外两个状态的值均为 2
For each state, we now have the expected return that's likely to follow if
对于每个状态 我们现在已经知道 如果智能体从该状态开始
the agent starts in that state and then follows the equal probable random policy.
然后遵循均等概率随机策略 期望回报是多少
The only problem here is that typically the state space is much
现在剩下的唯一问题是通常状态空间要大很多
larger so directly solving the system of equations is more difficult.
因此直接求解方程组更加困难
In this case, using an iterative method for solving the system generally works better.
在这种情况下 通常使用迭代方法求解方程组会更简单
So instead of solving the system directly,
因此我们不再直接求解方程组
what we can do is start off with a guess for the value of each state.
而是先猜测每个状态的值
It doesn't have to be any good and what's typically
并不要求有多精准
done is to set the value of each state to zero.
通常是将每个状态的值设为 0
Then we start by focusing our attention to one state.
然后重点关注一个状态
Say state S1.
例如状态 S1
And we'd like to improve our guess for the value of the state.
我们希望更精确地猜测该状态的值
To do this, we'll use the same Bellman equation from
为此 我们将使用之前的贝尔曼方程
before but we'll adopt it so it works as an update rule.
但是我们将调整该方程式 使其变成更新后的规则
Here, the capital V denotes our current guess for the value function.
在该方程式中 大写的 V 表示对值函数的当前猜测
We'll use this update rule to obtain a new guess for the value of state S1.
我们将使用这个更新的规则重新猜测状态 S1 的值
The idea is that we'll update a guess with
原理是通过猜测更新猜测
a guess where the current guesses for the values of
使用状态 S2 和状态 S3 值的当前猜测
states S2 and S3 are used to obtain a new guess for the value of state S1.
获得状态 S1 值的新猜测
So we plug in the estimates for the values of states S2 and S3 and when we do that,
我们代入状态 S2 和 S3 的估值
we get negative two which is our new guess for the value of
结果状态 S1 的值的新猜测是 -2
state S1 and will record that new value.
记下这个新值
Then, we'll do the same for the second state where we update
然后对第二个状态执行相同的流程
the guess for the value of state S2 using the value of state S1.
使用状态 S1 的值更新对状态 S2 的值的猜测
When we plug in the value,
代入该值后
we get one as our new estimate for the value of state S2 and we'll keep track of that.
得出状态 S2 的值的新猜测结果为 1 记下该值
Then onto state S3,
然后计算状态 S3
we update the value using our current estimate for the value of state S1.
使用状态 S1 的当前估值更新该值
Our new estimate is one which we can record.
新的估值是 1 记下该值
We won't need to update the value of state S4 since it's
我们不需要更新状态 S4 的值
a terminal state so it'll always have a value of zero.
因为它是最终状态 始终为 0
But we can loop back to the first state and continue to proceed in
但是我们可以回到第一个状态
this way with updating our guess
继续这一流程
based on the current guess for the values of the other states.
根据其他状态值的当前猜测结果更新对该状态的猜测
In this case, the value is updated to negative one which we can record.
此处 值更新为 -1 记录下来
Then we move on to state S2,
然后转到状态 S2 S3 等等
S3 and so on over and over and it turns out that
结果发现这种迭代算法
this iterative algorithm yields an estimate that converges to the true value function.
生成了越来越接近真实数值函数的估值
This is the idea behind an algorithm known as
这就是迭代策略评估算法的原理
Iterative Policy Evaluation and we'll go into much more detail soon.
我们很快就会详细讲解该算法